A Guide to the Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Medical Interests, Series K FA320
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Tuberculosis
  - Tuberculosis - Treatment - House of Rest, 1945-1955 (Box 17, Folder 135)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contribution; John D. Rockefeller 3rd conditional donation of $5,000; not collected.
  - Tuberculosis - Treatment - Altro Health and Rehabilitation Services, 1947-1955 (Box 17, Folder 136)
    Formerly Committee for the Care of the Jewish Tuberculous, Inc.
  - Tuberculosis - Tuberculosis Prevention for Children, 1911-1913, 1957-1961 (Box 17, Folder 137)
    New Jersey home to care for children of tubercular parents. John D. Rockefeller, Sr. contributes to building fund; John D. Rockefeller, Sr. and John D. Rockefeller, Jr. refuse to contribute to current funds. Mary French Rockefeller contributions, 1960-1961. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Sr., John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Starr J. Murphy.
  - Tuberculosis - New York Tuberculosis and Health Association, Inc., 1919-1961 (Box 17, Folder 138)
    Annual Rockefeller contribution to work, purchase of Christmas seals. 1950 named as final contribution year by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    71.2
  - Tuberculosis - New York Tuberculosis and Health Association, Inc. - Contributions, 1951-1960 (Box 18, Folder 139)
    Small annual gifts; Laurance S. Rockefeller donates $25,000 in 1960.
  - Tuberculosis - Westchester Tuberculosis and Public Health Association, 1916-1949 (Box 18, Folder 140)
    Annual contributions of $100 by John D. Rockefeller, Jr., 1920-1934, for work in Westchester. Nelson A. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Laurance S. Rockefeller gave small annual amounts. List of contributions from various members of the family. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Nelson A. Rockefeller.
    71.3
  - Tuberculosis - Westchester Tuberculosis and Public Health Association, 1916-1949 (Box 18, Folder 0140A)
    David Rockefeller gave small annual amounts. David Rockefeller gifts.
  - Tuberculosis - Westchester Tuberculosis and Public Health Association, 1950-1961 (Box 18, Folder 141)
    Nelson A. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Laurance S. Rockefeller gave small annual amounts. List of contributions from various members of the family. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Nelson A. Rockefeller.
  - Tuberculosis - Westchester Tuberculosis and Public Health Association, 1950-1961 (Box 18, Folder 0141A)
  - Tuberculosis - Saranac Lake Study and Craft Guild, 1947-1949 (Box 18, Folder 142)
    Appeals for aid to Laurance S. Rockefeller, all declined on advice of Arthur W. Packard. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard.
    71.5
- Hospitals
  - Hospitals - Miscellaneous, 1907-1947 (Box 18, Folder 143)
    Appeals for contributions from various hospitals; denial of appeals, referral of others to Rockefeller Foundation or Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research, contributions made to some. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Thomas B. Appleget, Arthur Woods, Arthur W. Packard, Dana S. Creel, Laurance S. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
    Auburn City Hospital, New York, 1947 Babies' Hospital, London, 1923-1924 Baptist Hospital, Winston-Salem, 1947 Benedictine Hospital of Kingston, New York, 1945-1954 Centro Medico of Caracas (Dr. J. J. Bentata), 1946 Forest Hills Hospital Association, Cleveland, Ohio, 1945 Franklin County Memorial, Maine, 1946 Grandview Tuberculosis Hospital, Oil City, Pennsylvania, 1907 Greater Cleveland Hospital Fund Miss M. Harrais, proposed hospital, Alaska, 1951 Infants Hospital, Westminster, London, England, 1924 Lawrence Hospital, New York, 1950 Leonard Wood Memorial, proposed leprosarium, 1947 Long Island College of Medicine, Brooklyn, New York, 1939 Massachusetts General Hospital, 1947-1961 New Haven Hospital, New Haven, Connecticut, 1946 North Carolina Baptist Hospital, Post Graduate School of Pastoral Care, 1947-1954 North Country Community Hospital, Glen Cove, Long Island, New York (clippings), 1946-1948 Northwestern Anti-Tuberculosis League, Pennsylvania, 1917 Ossining Hospital, New York (clippings), 1952-1955 Pascack Valley Hospital, New Jersey, 1946-1951 *Dr. Peyton, Mercy Hospital, Pennsylvania, 1939-1940 Provident Hospital, Chicago, 1947 Provident Hospital and Free Dispensary, Baltimore, Maryland Rockland State Hospital, Orangeburg, New York, 1940 School for Nurses at Mercy Hospital, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1928 St. Francis Sanatorium for Cardiac Children, New York, 1946-1952 Saint Lo Hospital, France, 1947-1955 Strong Memorial Hospital, New York, Dr. S. L. Warren, 1940 Valdez Community Hospital, Valdez, Alaska, 1947 Westchester County Hospitals (clippings), 1947
    An asterisk (*) indicates hospital received Rockefeller contribution.
  - Hospitals - Miscellaneous, 1948-1949 (Box 18, Folder 144)
    Bicur Cholim Hospital, Jerusalem, 1948-1949 Davis Memorial Hospital, West Virginia, 1949 Dobbs Ferry Hospital, New York (clippings mostly), 1945-1954 East Tennessee Baptist Hospital, 1948 Grace Cottage Hospital, Vermont, 1949 Hillcrest Medical Center, Oklahoma (Tri-State College), 1948-1958 Madison Rural Sanitarium & Hospital, Tenessee, 1948 Massachusetts General Hospital, 1947-1961 Miami Heart Institute, Inc., Col. Mettler, 1949-1950 National Cancer Hospital of America, 1949-1950 Nebraska Methodist Hospital, 1949 New Jersey Orthopaedic Hospital, 1952 New York Society of Neurosurgery (clipping), 1948 New York Hospital Study (clipping), 1948 North Country Community Hospital, Glen Cove, Long Island, New York (clipping), 1946-1948 Ossining Hospital, New York (clipping), 1952-1955 Pascack Valey Hospital, New Jersey, 1946-1951 Paul de Kruif Project, California, 1949 Placid Memorial Hospital, New York, 1948 St. Francis Sanatorium for Cardiac Children, New York, 1946-1952 *St. Johns Hospital, Jackson Hole, Wyoming, 1952-1957 St. Michaels Hospital, New Jersey, 1953 Mr. C. E. Smock, Kentucky, 1949 United Mission Hospital in Lahore, India, 1948
    An asterick (*) indicates hospital received Rockefeller contribution.
  - Hospitals - Miscellaneous, 1950 (Box 19, Folder 145)
    Boston Evening Clinic & Hospital, Massachusetts, 1950 Dr. E. T. Carsten, Guatemala, 1950 Christ Hospital, New Jersey, 1950 Christian Medical College & Hospital, India, 1954-1955 Community Memorial Hospital Fund, Virginia, 1950 Dobbs Ferry Hospital, New York (clippings mostly), 1945-1954 Emerald-Hodgson Hospital, Tennessee, 1950 Friendship Clinic, Mississippi, 1950 General Hospital of Valley Stream, Long Island, New York, 1950 Groton Community Hospital, Massachusetts, 1950 Hiroshima Memorial Hospital (Mrs. Sproul), 1950 Miss Matilda Johns, regarding Negro hospital drive, 1950 Kent County Memorial Hospital, Rhode Island, 1950 Mrs. M. Kinzie, Cleveland, 1950 Lawrence Hospital, New York, 1950 Mr. J. J. Livingston, proposed Negro hospital, 1950 Miami Heart Institute, Inc., Col. Mettler, 1949-1950 National Cancer Hospital of America, 1949-1950 North Shore Hospital, New York, 1955 Northwestern Hospital, Mrs. Anna Rosenberg, 1950 Norwalk Hospital, Connecticut, 1950 Norwegian Hospital, New York City, 1951 Ossining Hospital, New York (clipping), 1952-1955 Patrick Henry Hospital for Chronically Ill, Virginia, 1950 North Country Community Hospital, Glen Cove, Long Island, New York (clipping), 1946-1948 *Richmond Memorial Hospital, Virginia, 1950 St. Francis Sanatorium for Cardiac Children, New York, 1946-1952 *St. Johns Hospital, Jakcson Hole, Wyoming, 1952-1957 St. John's Riverside Hospital, New York, 1950 St. Louis Children's Hospital, 1950-1952 Mrs. J. M. Sperzel, 1951 Uplands Sanatarium, Tennessee, 1950-1951 Vassar Brothers Hospital, New York, 1950 Women's Hospital, Cleveland, 1950
  - Hospitals - Miscellaneous, 1951-1952 (Box 19, Folder 146)
    Aitken Community Hospital, Minnesota, 1951 Alexian Brothers Hospital, Missouri, 1951 American College of Surgeons (clippings), 1953 Benjamin Rose Institute, Cleveland, 1952 Berkshire Medical Group, Massachusetts, 1951 Bertrand Chaffee Hospital, New York, 1951 Booker T. Washington Community Hospital, New Jersey, 1951 Boston State Hospital, Massachusetts, 1952 *British-American Hospital, Madrid, 1952-1954 Brooklyn Women's Hospital, New York City, 1951 Christian Medical College & Hospital, India, 1954-1955 *Community Hospital at Glen Cove, New York (earlier called North Country Community Hospital), 1948-1959 Dixie Hospital, Virginia, 1955 Dobbs Ferry Hospital, New York (clippings mostly), 1945-1954 Elliott Hospital, 1952 Florida Interracial Hospital (Clipping), 1951 Greenwich Hospital, Connecticut (clipping), 1951 Mrs. W. H. Hardy, proposed Negro hospital, Mississippi, 1951 Miss M. Harrais, proposed hospital, Alaska, 1951 Hospital for the Mentally Ill of Natal, Brazil, 1952 International University Hospital, Paris, 1951 Leonardtown proposed Hospital, Mr. B. O. Callis, 1952 Long Island Jewish Hospital, 1951 Maine Medical Center, 1952 *Massachusetts General Hospital, 1947-1961 Memorial Hospital, Maryland, 1951 National Cancer Hospital of America, 1949-1950 New Jersey Orthopaedic Hospital, 1952 North Shore Hospital, New York, 1955 Norwegian Hospital, New York City, 1951 Nyack Hospital, New York, 1954 Ossining Hospital, New York (clipping), 1952-1955 Pascack Valley Hospital, New Jersey, 1946-1951 Milford Hospital, Milford, Connecticut 1951 *Richmond Memorial Hospital, Virginia, 1950 St. Francis Health Resort, New Jersey, 1951 St. Francis Sanatorium for Cardiac Children, New York, 1946-1952 *St, Johns Hospital, Jackson Hole, Wyoming, 1952-1957 St. Joseph's Memorial Hospital & Home for Aged, Wisconsin, 1951 Saint Lo Hospital, France, 1947-1955 St. Louis Children's Hospital, 1950-1952 Swedish Hospital, Washington, 1952 University Sanitorium of Belgium, 1951 St. Mary Convent, Mobile, Alabama, 1951 Upper Manhattan Medical Center (clipping), 1952 Mrs. H. G. Wager, 1952 Watson Hospital for Crippled Children, Pennsylvania, 1951 White Memorial Hospital & Clinic, California, 1951
  - Hospitals - Miscellaneous, 1953-1954 (Box 19, Folder 147)
    Addison Keyette Club, Addison, Michigan, 1954 American College of Surgeons (clippings), 1953 Benedictine Hospital of Kingston, New York, 1945-1954 Blessed Martin de Porres Hospital, Alabama (Sister M. Cornelia), 1951-1953 *Booth Memorial Hospital, New York City, 1956 *British American Hospital, Madrid, 1952-1954 Brooklyn Hospitals (clippings), 1954 *Children's Hospital of Philadelphia, 1953-1961 Chilton Memorial Hospital, New Jersey, 1954 Djabo Maternity General Hospital, Colorado, 1953 Englewood Hospital, New Jersey, 1953 Friendship Sanatorium, North Carolina, 1954 Gogebic Area Memorial Hospital Association, Michigan, 1953 Holy Cross Hospital, Florida, 1953 Home & Hospital of the Daughters of Jacob, Geriatrics Insitute, Weinstein Pavilion, 1954 King Edward VII Memorial Hospital, Bermuda, 1954-1955 Dr. Z. Lihr, Finland, 1954 Memorial Hospital, New York, 1959 National Cancer Hospital of America, 1949-1950 North Carolina Baptist Hospital, Post Graduate School of Pastoral Care, 1947-1954 North Shore Hospital, New York, 1955 Nyack Hospital, New York, 1954 Perth-Amboy General Hospital, 1953 North Country Community Hospital, Glen Cove, Long Island, New York (clipping), 1946-1948 Memorial Hospital Trust Association, 1954 Pfiffer Memorial Hospital, Bolivia (Miss E. M. Elliott), 1954 Rahway Memorial Hospital, New Jersey, 1953 Rockland State Hospital Chapel Fund, New York 1940-1957 St. Agnes Hospital, New York, 1954 *St. Johns Hospital, Jackson Hole, Wyoming, 1952-1957 Saint Lo Hospital, France, 1947-1955 St. Michaels Hospital, New Jersey, 1953 Southside Comminity Hospital, Virginia 1954 Wilmington General Hospital, Delaware, 1953 Winter Park Hospital, Florida, 1954
  - Hospitals - Miscellaneous, 1955 (Box 19, Folder 148)
    Belleville Medical Center (Mr. John F. Kidde), 1955 *Booth Memorial Hospital, New York City, 1956 Butler Hospital, Rhode Island, 1956-1957 *Children's Hospital of Philaelphia, 1953-1961 Christian Medical College & Hospital, India, 1954-1955 Mrs. L. A. Crandall, proposed hospital, California, 1955 Dixie Hospital, Virginia, 1955 *Hartford Hospital, Connecticut, 1955-1956 Hospital Fact-Finding Service, Connecticut, 1956 Institute of Applied Biology (clipping), 1955 King Edward VII Memorial Hospital, Bermuda, 1954-1955 Mason Memorial Hospital, Bahrain, Arabia, 1955 Massachusetts Memorial Hospitals Medical Center, 1960 Miners Hospital, Pennsylvania (clipping), 1955 Neponsit Hospital, Mrs. H. R. Tanner, New York City, 1955 Peekskill Hospital (Friendly Hospital), 1955-1958 Rockland State Hospital Chapel Fund, New York, 1940-1957 Roger Williams General hospital, Rhode Island, 1955 *St. Johns Hospital, Jackson Hole, Wyoming, 1952-1957 Saint Lo Hospital, France, 1947-1955 St. Luke's Hospital, North Carolina, 1955 St. Margaret's Hospital, Kansas, 1955 St. Mary's Hospital, Oklahoma, 1955 St. Vincent Hospital, New Mexico, 1955 Spears Chiroprractic Sanatarium, Florida, 1955-1956 Toronto East General Hospital, 1954 Sacred Heart Hospital, Chester, Pennsylvania, 1956 Salvation Army Hospital, Queens, New York, 1956 Whidden Memorial Hospital, Massachusetts, 1955 Will Rogers Hospital, New York (clipping), 1955 Woonsocket Hospital, Rhode Island, 1955
  - Hospitals - Miscellaneous, 1956 (Box 19, Folder 149)
    Alice Hyde Memorial Hospital, New York, 1956 American Memorial Hospital, France, 1956 Andrews Memorial Hospital, Kingston, Jamaica, 1948 *Booth Memorial Hospital, New York City, 1956 Butler Hospital, Rhode Island, 1956-1957 *Children's Hospital of Philadelphia, 1953-1961 *Community Hospital at Glen Cove, New York (earlier called North Country Community Hospital), 1948-1959 *Crotched Mountain Foundation, New Hampshire, 1956-1959 Miss T. Ford, Florida, 1956 Franklin Foundation Hospital, Louisiana, 1956 *Hartford Hospital, Connecticut, 1955-1956 Jones Memorial Hospital, Pennsylvania, 1956 Manchester Memorial Hospital, Connecticut, 1956 *New England Center Hospital, New England Medical Center, 1946-1961 Presbyterian Hospital, Puerto Rico, 1956-1958 Rip Van Winkle Clinic, 1950 Rockland State Hospital Chapel Fund, New York, 1940-1957 St. Elizabeth Hospital, Nova Scotia, 1956 *St. Johns Hospital, Jackson Hole, Wyoming, 1952-1957 Saint Lo Hospital, France, 1947-1955 Spears Chiropractic Sanatarium, Florida, 1955-1956 State Hospital, North Carolina, 1956 Staten Island Hospital, 1956 Watts Hospital Course in Practical Nursing, 1956
  - Hospitals - Miscellaneous, 1957 (Box 19, Folder 150)
    Bishop Randall Hospital, Wyoming, 1957 City of Hope, New York City Chapter, 1956-1961 *Community Hospital at Glen Clove, New York (earlier called North Country Community Hospital, 1948-1959 Crippled Children's Hospital, Virginia, 1957-1961 *Crotched Mountain Foundation, New Hampshire 1956-1959 Deborah Sanatorium, 1957 Geauga Hospital Association, Ohio, 1957 Houston Tuberculosis Hospital, 1957 King Edward VII Memorial Hospital, Bermuda, 1954-1955 Knox County General Hospital, Maine, 1957 Mercy Hospital, Maryland, 1928-1957 Orange Memorial Hospital, Florida, 1957 Ottauquechee Health Center Peekskill Hospital (Friendly Hospital), 1955-1958 Perry County Health Center, Arkansas, 1957 Presbyterian Hospital, Puerto Rico, 1956-1958 Rip Van Winkle Clinic, 1956-1957 Rockland State Hospital Chapel Fund, New York, 1940-1957 *St. Johns Hospital, Jackson Hole, Wyoming, 1952-1957 St. John's Hospital, Missouri, 1950-1957 St. Joseph's Hospital, Texas, 1957 Sisters of Charity of Seaton Hil, 1957 Whiting Clinic, Indiana, 1957
  - Hospitals - Miscellaneous, 1958-1959 (Box 20, Folder 151)
    Baptist Memorial Hospital, Missouri, 1958 Children's Convalescent Hospital, 1958 Children's Hospital of Philadelphia, 1953-1961 City of Hope, Los Angeles Chapter, 1958 City of Hope, New York City Chapter, 1956-1961 *Community Hospital at Glen Cove, New York (earlier called North Country Community Hospital) 1948-1959 Cottage Hospital, New Hampshire, 1958 *Crotched Mountain Foundation, New Hampshire, 1956-1959 *Friends of Pusan Children's Hospital, Korea, 1959-1961 Grace Hospital, Cleveland, 1958 Hillcrest Medical Center, Oklahoma (Tri-State College), 1948-1958 Institute for Living, Connecticut, 1958 Kingsbridge Veteran's Center, MacGregor Rehabilitation Center, Bronx, New York, 1959 Memorial Hospital, New York, 1959 Northern Dutchess Health Center, New York, 1958 Ottauquechee Health Center Peekskill Hospital (Friendly Hospital), 1955-1958 Presbyterian Hospital, Puerto Rico, 1956-1958 St. Joseph Hospital, Maine, 1959 St. Joseph's Hospital, Illinois, 1958 State Department of Mental Hygiene (clipping), 1958 *United Mission Hospital in Nepal, 1959-1960
  - Hospitals - Miscellaneous, 1960-1961 (Box 20, Folder 152)
    *Albany Medical Center, 1961 Battle Creek Sanitarium & Hospital, Michigan, 1961 City of Hope, New York City Chapter, 1956-1961 City of St. Jude, Alabama, 1961 Crippled Children's Hospital, Virginia, 1957-1961 Dorado Hospital, Puerto Rico, 1961 Eleanor Roosevelt Cancer Foundation, 1960 Epp Memorial Hospital, Ohio, 1960 *Friends of Pusan Children's Hospital, Korea, 1959-1961 Hillcrest General Hospital, New York, 1960 Hospital Santa Monica, Brazil, 1961 Iran Medical Center, New York, New York, 1961 Mamie Dowd Eisenhower Osteopathic Hospital, Colorado, 1960 *Massachusetts General Hospital, 1947-1961 Masschusetts Memorial Hospitals Medical Center, 1960 Massachusetts Osteopathic Hospital, 1961 *New England Center Hospital, New England Medical Center, 1946-1961 Ottauquechee Health Center Presbyterian-St. Luke's Hospital, Chicago, 1960 Putnam County Hospitals merger, 1960 St. Croix Hospital, Virgin Islands, 1961 St. Jude Hospital, Tennessee, 1960-1961 *United Mission Hospital in Nepal, 1959-1960 *Veterans Administration Hospital, New York, 1960 Westerly Hospital, Rhode Island, 1960 Yale Psychiatric Institute, 1961
  - Hospitals - Miscellaneous - Memorial Hospital, Phoenix, Arizona, 1957 (Box 20, Folder 153)
    Laurance S. Rockefeller gift to hospital.
  - Hospitals - New York City (A-L), 1927-1950 (Box 20, Folder 154)
    Work of Bureau for Blood Transfusion; declination of appeal for contributions. Correspondents include Thomas B. Appleget, Arthur Woods, Thomas M. Debevoise, Kenneth Chorley, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Arthur W. Packard.
    Association for Improvement of Mental Hospitals, Inc., 1950 Beth Israel Hospital, 1941 Bronx Hospital, 1927
  - Hospitals - New York City (M-Z), 1927-1950 (Box 20, Folder 155)
  - Hospitals - New York City (A-Z), 1951-1961 (Box 20, Folder 156)
  - Hospitals - New York City - New York Society for the Relief of the Ruptured and Crippled/Hospital for Special Surgery, 1943-1961 (Box 21, Folder 157)
    Needs of the Hospital; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s contribution to research fund to be constituted as a permanent memorial to Dr. Virgil P. Gibney; contributions to budget. Declination of appeals for contributions. Correspondents include Mary Rockefeller, Willard S. Richardson, Robert W. Gumbel, Thomas M. Debevoise, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Hospitals - New York City - City Hospital, Welfare Island, 1924-1954 (Box 21, Folder 158)
    Family gift of radio to Dr. Bacon for use of patients. Correspondents include Abraham Flexner, Robert W. Gumbel, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Hospitals - American Hospital Association, 1928-1960 (Box 21, Folder 159)
    Declination of appeals for contributions; John D. Rockefeller 3rd contributions to public relations department, 1958. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Arthur W. Packard, Thomas B. Appleget.
  - Hospitals - American Hospital of Paris, 1923-1961 (Box 21, Folder 160)
    Needs of hospital. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s anonymous contribution; Abby Rockefeller Mauz contributions. Correspondents include Arthur Woods, Willard S. Richardson.
  - Hospitals - American Hospital of Paris, 1923-1961 (Box 21, Folder 0160A)
    David Rockefeller's contributions, election as Life Member.
  - Hospitals - American Hospital of Paris - John D. Rockefeller, Sr. and John D. Rockefeller, Jr. $10,000 Pledge, 1915-1920 (Box 21, Folder 161)
    Pledge to underwrite expenses of American Ambulance Hospital in Paris; transferral of money to American Hospital in Paris. Correspondents include Starr J. Murphy, Willard S. Richardson, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Hospitals - Baltimore Provident Hospital and Dispensary, 1927-1932, 1957 (Box 21, Folder 162)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s pledge to hospital dedicated to training Negro interns and nurses and providing post-graduate work for Negro doctors. Correspondents include Abraham Flexner, Thomas B. Appleget, Arthur W. Packard, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Dr. J. M. T. Finney.
  - Hospitals - Baylor University, Hospital and Medical College, 1934-1959 (Box 21, Folder 163)
    Needs of College and Hospital, request for contribution. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, Thomas M. Debevoise, Dana S. Creel.
  - Hospitals - Bayonne, New Jersey Hospital, 1920-1956 (Box 21, Folder 164)
    Erection of new buildings of Bayonne Hospital and Dispensary; survey of city hospital conditions. Pledges by Standard Oil Co. of New Jersey, Vacuum Oil Co., and Tide Water Oil Co.; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s pledge. Correspondents include C. J. Hicks, Willard S. Richardson, Starr J. Murphy, Charles O. Heydt, Thomas M. Appleget.
  - Hospitals - Beekman Street Hospital, New York City, 1925-1956 (Box 21, Folder 165)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s pledge for enlargement and equipment and current expenses. Correspondents include Willard S. Richardson, Arthur W. Packard, Thomas M. Appleget.
  - Hospitals - Bellevue Hospital, New York City, 1930-1961 (Box 22, Folder 166)
    Appeal for contributions to various clinics of Hospital. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. 1959 gift. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Arthur W. Packard, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
  - Hospitals - Bellevue Hospital, New York City, 1930-1961 (Box 22, Folder 0166A)
  - Hospitals - Bellevue Hospital, New York City - Just One Break, Inc., 1953-1961 (Box 22, Folder 167)
    Laurance S. Rockefeller's contributions. Correspondents include Laurance S. Rockefeller, Capt. Percy Lawson-Johnson.
  - Hospitals - Bellevue Hospital, New York City - Social Services Auxiliary, 1941-1961 (Box 22, Folder 168)
    Abby Aldrich Rockefeller's contributions to Auxiliary. David Rockefeller's contributions; Mary French Rockefeller's contributions. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Hospitals - Bellevue Hospital, New York City - Social Services Auxiliary, 1941-1961 (Box 22, Folder 0168A)
  - Hospitals - Broad Street Hospital, New York City/Downtown Hospital, 1915-1941 (Box 22, Folder 169)
    Work of the Hospital; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s contribution. Correspondents include Starr J. Murphy, Willard S. Richardson, Nelson A. Rockefeller, C. J. Hicks.
  - Hospitals - Brooklyn (A-Z), 1927-1960 (Box 22, Folder 170)
    Building Fund campaign of St. John's Hospital; declination of appeals from other hospitals for contributions. Correspondents include Robert W. Gumbel, Thomas M. Appleget.
  - Hospitals - Brooklyn - Swedish Hospital, 1928-1938 (Box 22, Folder 171)
    Financial needs of Hospital; declination of appeals for contributions. Correspondents include Robert W. Gumbel, Arthur W. Packard, Thomas M. Appleget.
  - Hospitals - Charity Hospital, Cleveland, Ohio, 1904-1915 (Box 22, Folder 172)
    Appeals, John D. Rockefeller, Sr. contributions. Correspondents include Frederick T. Gates, Starr J. Murphy, John D. Rockefeller, Sr.
  - Hospitals - Charles F. Kettering Memorial Hospital, 1959-1961 (Box 22, Folder 173)
    Laurance S. Rockefeller pledge of approximately $50,000, March 19, 1960. Correspondents include Laurance S. Rockefeller, Eugene W. Kettering, Alfred P. Sloan.
  - Hospitals - Children's Asthma Research Institute and Hospital, 1955-1961 (Box 22, Folder 174)